<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Blog of Alex Oberhauser]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.alex-oberhauser.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.alex-oberhauser.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-09-24T23:55:33+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.alex-oberhauser.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Alex Oberhauser]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[alex.oberhauser@networld.to]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[<small>A day in my life as an entrepreneur:</small> <br/><strong>Sigimera Ltd. in Amsterdam</strong>]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.alex-oberhauser.com/2013/09/22/a-day-in-my-life-as-an-entrepreneur-new-context/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-22T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.alex-oberhauser.com/2013/09/22/a-day-in-my-life-as-an-entrepreneur-new-context</id>
    
      












      <link rel="payment" href="https://flattr.com/submit/auto?url=http%3A%2F%2Fblog.alex-oberhauser.com%2F2013%2F09%2F22%2Fa-day-in-my-life-as-an-entrepreneur-new-context%2F&amp;user_id=obale&amp;title=%3Csmall%3EA+day+in+my+life+as+an+entrepreneur%3A%3C%2Fsmall%3E+%3Cbr%2F%3E%3Cstrong%3ESigimera+Ltd.+in+Amsterdam%3C%2Fstrong%3E&amp;category=text&amp;description=Alex+Oberhauser+is+a+social+tech-entrepreneur+and+graduated+computer+scientist.+He+is+co-founder+and+CEO+of+%3Ca+href%3D%22http%3A%2F%2Fwww.sigimera.com%22+target%3D%22_blank%22%3ESigimera+Ltd.%3C%2Fa%3E+and+founded+the+software+incubator+project+%3Ca+href%3D%22http%3A%2F%2Fnetworld.to%22+target%3D%22_blank%22%3ENetworld%3C%2Fa%3E.%3Cbr%2F%3E%0A&amp;tags=day-in-my-life-as-entrepreneur%2Centrepreneur" type="text/html" />
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It is more than a month ago, I published the last blog post. Let me get you updated what
happened during this time. There were two major, somehow interconnected, changes. The first is
the move of myself to Amsterdam (the rest of the team stays in Austria and the company legal
residence in the UK). The second is the decision to stop all marketing activities and get
back to the drawing board. In this blog post I will try to explain to you why this decisions were
made and what consequences they have.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Let me start with my move to Amsterdam. I will continue there with my Master studies at the VU Amsterdam,
but that is only half of the truth. The other is that I will try to get in touch with the startup
community. Not so much through startup events, but more directly with other entrepreneurs, at least for
now. That was also the reason why I was in the last few weeks busy with the move and the restructuring
of our communication means. As I have explained in one of my last blog post the team is the most
crucial part, one reason more to continue with our internal meetings, nevertheless where we are.
Until now that works pretty well&hellip; Actually better as all other video conferences before. The reason
is the fast Internet connection and the updated equipment for this purpose.</p>

<p>The consequence for Sigimera Ltd. is that we have now an unofficial office in Amsterdam. One
advantage is the direct connection to one of the biggest Internet Exchange point worldwide.
Additional it extends our on-site impact to yet another country. One change was also the
restructuring of our telephone system. Now we have a landline phone number in the Netherlands. This number
can and will be redirect to all (or some) of our business partners, nevertheless where they are currently
and without additional costs for the caller. This phone number allows us to travel around the world
and get all calls without roaming costs. If necessary we will get other numbers in the countries
where we are active. This is a big advantage for such a company as Sigimera Ltd. We have currently
no official office and are spread across two to four countries (until now), nevertheless we are able to
communicate in a cheap and reliable way with all stakeholders. Combined with other communication means,
e.g. for weekly internal meetings, code quality and software planning platforms, this makes our company
structure very flexible and lets us adapt to the ever changing market.</p>

<p>Now that we have a flexible company structure that allows us to communication across country borders
and work together in collaborative way, it is time to focus on our business idea. The current plan is
to go one or two steps back, stop the past marketing efforts for the Donation Service and build on top
of this Donation Service a campaign management system. This extends not only our target market,
but gives us also a little bit time to stabilize our company structure and maybe get new business partner.
If you have worried in the past weeks if Sigimera is alive, I can you assure that it is and that more
than ever.</p>

<p>As you can see we are no conventional company and are able to organize our structures on the go, as every
startup should. Our flexibility and commitment to our ideas gives as good base for further development.</p>

<p>As always please let me know what you think. Do you face the same challenges? How do you solve them? What
do you think about startup without office space? Looking forward to an interesting conversation and
discussion.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[<small>A Day in My Life as an Entrepreneur:</small><br/> <strong>It&#8217;s all about the team</strong>]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.alex-oberhauser.com/2013/08/03/a-day-in-my-life-as-an-entrepreneur-its-all-about-the-team/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-03T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.alex-oberhauser.com/2013/08/03/a-day-in-my-life-as-an-entrepreneur-its-all-about-the-team</id>
    
      












      <link rel="payment" href="https://flattr.com/submit/auto?url=http%3A%2F%2Fblog.alex-oberhauser.com%2F2013%2F08%2F03%2Fa-day-in-my-life-as-an-entrepreneur-its-all-about-the-team%2F&amp;user_id=obale&amp;title=%3Csmall%3EA+Day+in+My+Life+as+an+Entrepreneur%3A%3C%2Fsmall%3E%3Cbr%2F%3E+%3Cstrong%3EIt%27s+all+about+the+team%3C%2Fstrong%3E&amp;category=text&amp;description=Alex+Oberhauser+is+a+social+tech-entrepreneur+and+graduated+computer+scientist.+He+is+co-founder+and+CEO+of+%3Ca+href%3D%22http%3A%2F%2Fwww.sigimera.com%22+target%3D%22_blank%22%3ESigimera+Ltd.%3C%2Fa%3E+and+founded+the+software+incubator+project+%3Ca+href%3D%22http%3A%2F%2Fnetworld.to%22+target%3D%22_blank%22%3ENetworld%3C%2Fa%3E.%3Cbr%2F%3E%0A&amp;tags=day-in-my-life-as-entrepreneur%2Centrepreneur" type="text/html" />
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In order to be ready for the challenges as entrepreneur I try to learn as much as possible from
different sources. One, very useful, source was, and is, the uprise and most time also downfall of other
startups. One important thing that I have learned is that
a startup is all about the people. With the right people you get the right know-how and the right
environment to overcome the biggest challenges.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>If you have not the right people for the right job you will fail. <em>Right</em> is more about attitude
as about academic skills. Don&rsquo;t get me wrong, academic skills are a must, but everybody in your
team should be able to get them on the go. As described in previous posts you have to extend your skills
outside your field of expertise. It helps if you have a heterogeneous team that is able to exchange
knowledge. Develop your expertise the same way as you would develop software in an agile way. The following
steps are a simplified way how such a process for knowledge exchange can look like:</p>

<ol>
<li>Define a challenge that you want solve, e.g. with a clear problem statement</li>
<li>Learn as much as possible about this topic.</li>
<li>Listen and discuss with people around you, maybe you have an expert in your team or you can get feedback
from somebody outside.</li>
<li>Evaluate all knowledge that (you think) you have about this topic.</li>
<li>If your knowledge is sufficient to solve the challenge you are good, otherwise get back to
point 3.</li>
</ol>


<p>As you can see you extend your skills in an iterative way. The most important, but also hardest part
is point 4. Nobody likes to admit that he or she is wrong or that the own knowledge is not accurate or
incomplete. But without acknowledging your failures you are not able to learn, at least not so fast as you
could. To be honest I am not as good as I should with this point, but I try to get better each day.</p>

<p>Now we know how we can improve our skills via knowledge exchange. This makes us to an important
member of our team. But what is about the right attitude? My personal feeling is that the right attitude is
crucial to survive, at least for a young startup. It is the breeding ground for innovation. Do you really
want to be part of an startup? The right answer should be YES, at least for a few years. You should not miss this
opportunity.</p>

<p>It can be a roller coaster ride, with a lot of downs and ups, especially if you have to motivate yourself each single day&hellip;
But it is definitely worth it. You invest a few years of your life to learn and improve your skills and not to forget your
personality&hellip; hopefully to something better. Dependent on your goals you have maybe also a positive impact on your society.
We all are getting older each day and our priorities change. This is also the
reason why I have decided to take the chance to be an entrepreneur now and for the next few years. Independent if it succeeds
or fails I will shift for sure to a more stable life in a later point in time, but I definitely don&rsquo;t want to miss the
possibility to be an entrepreneur.</p>

<p>Please let me know in the comments or via other means how you motivate yourself and your team. Looking
forward to other views about this topic.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[<small>A day in my life as an entrepreneur:</small> <br/><strong>The Motivation</strong>]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.alex-oberhauser.com/2013/07/17/a-day-in-my-life-as-an-entrepreneur-the-motivation/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-17T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.alex-oberhauser.com/2013/07/17/a-day-in-my-life-as-an-entrepreneur-the-motivation</id>
    
      












      <link rel="payment" href="https://flattr.com/submit/auto?url=http%3A%2F%2Fblog.alex-oberhauser.com%2F2013%2F07%2F17%2Fa-day-in-my-life-as-an-entrepreneur-the-motivation%2F&amp;user_id=obale&amp;title=%3Csmall%3EA+day+in+my+life+as+an+entrepreneur%3A%3C%2Fsmall%3E+%3Cbr%2F%3E%3Cstrong%3EThe+Motivation%3C%2Fstrong%3E&amp;category=text&amp;description=Alex+Oberhauser+is+a+social+tech-entrepreneur+and+graduated+computer+scientist.+He+is+co-founder+and+CEO+of+%3Ca+href%3D%22http%3A%2F%2Fwww.sigimera.com%22+target%3D%22_blank%22%3ESigimera+Ltd.%3C%2Fa%3E+and+founded+the+software+incubator+project+%3Ca+href%3D%22http%3A%2F%2Fnetworld.to%22+target%3D%22_blank%22%3ENetworld%3C%2Fa%3E.%3Cbr%2F%3E%0A&amp;tags=day-in-my-life-as-entrepreneur%2Centrepreneur" type="text/html" />
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After the first post in this series &ndash;
<a href="http://blog.alex-oberhauser.com/2013/07/15/a-day-in-my-life-as-an-entrepreneur-the-begining/">The Beginning</a> &ndash;
I was asked to write something about my motivation and how my days look
like. Where should I start&hellip; Do you don&rsquo;t dream about working without breaks 24/7 and have a job
where you don&rsquo;t get money, but you have to pay for it&hellip; Really not!?! Then
maybe the profession of an entrepreneur is not the right choice for
you. At least not in the startup boostrap phase.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>But let me explain what my personal motivation is. As described in the last post I have
started with small projects during my
studies. The motivation there was to deepen my knowledge in a practical way.
Pretty fast this attitude has developed further to see how far I can go. In the beginning
it was only about programming software, but after a while I have developed
this further to software engineering and how I can organize
the programming more effective. During this time I have also researched what
is needed for a company formation. This knowledge was really handy this year,
by far not complete, but handy.</p>

<p>And what is the motivation today? Of course the experience that you get and the diversity
of knowledge that is needed is one of the main reasons. You learn nearly each day something new.
But maybe more important is the fun that
it makes to build something from scratch. If something does not work&hellip; You
change it. If you are stuck with something&hellip; You switch temporary to another task
and return later to this challenging issue. Additional the gained experience helps to
overcome harder times. It helps also that our company should have a social
impact. I wouldn&rsquo;t say it is easier to do something good, but it lets you
sleep better and it motivates.</p>

<p>Motivation is essential, but how does my day look like? It is maybe more flexible as the average person&rsquo;s working day.
I work when I am ready
and not when I must, at least not for my company. I try to combine as much as
possible and interconnect tasks. This safes time. Additional I have developed
a feeling when I have to stop working on a task where I am stuck. Experience shows
that if I come back later I find by far faster a solution as working without break
on it. Each software developer experiences sooner or later that he or she
has broken more things than fixed if forced to work on a problem at the wrong time.
This costs in the long term more time as it safes. We all know it deep inside.
What additional helps is that most skills learned in computer science are applicable for
other areas as well. This makes the switch to other areas not as hard as it seams. And
that is crucial for entrepreneurship. You can&rsquo;t say I don&rsquo;t do that, because I am only
a software engineer or a XYZ, or whatever your profession is. If you and your team
don&rsquo;t tackle the challenges who else should!?!</p>

<p>Not convinced yet? I have one last motivation that sounds naive, but that should not scare you too much.
Calculated naivety is a powerful tool.</p>

<p>If everybody thinks that he or she is to stupid, to weak, to unimportant, or whatever to have
an impact and change the world, who the hell dictates your day-to-day life? If you think
about it a company is in our society the perfect mean to have an impact. Also if you fail it
is always better than not to have tried. I take my chance&hellip; What about you?</p>

<blockquote><p>A journey of a thousand miles begins with a single step.<br/>
<em><small>by Lao-tzu, The Way of Lao-tzu</small></em></p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[<small>A day in my life as an entrepreneur:</small> <br/><strong>The Beginning</strong>]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.alex-oberhauser.com/2013/07/15/a-day-in-my-life-as-an-entrepreneur-the-begining/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-15T08:08:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.alex-oberhauser.com/2013/07/15/a-day-in-my-life-as-an-entrepreneur-the-begining</id>
    
      












      <link rel="payment" href="https://flattr.com/submit/auto?url=http%3A%2F%2Fblog.alex-oberhauser.com%2F2013%2F07%2F15%2Fa-day-in-my-life-as-an-entrepreneur-the-begining%2F&amp;user_id=obale&amp;title=%3Csmall%3EA+day+in+my+life+as+an+entrepreneur%3A%3C%2Fsmall%3E+%3Cbr%2F%3E%3Cstrong%3EThe+Beginning%3C%2Fstrong%3E&amp;category=text&amp;description=Alex+Oberhauser+is+a+social+tech-entrepreneur+and+graduated+computer+scientist.+He+is+co-founder+and+CEO+of+%3Ca+href%3D%22http%3A%2F%2Fwww.sigimera.com%22+target%3D%22_blank%22%3ESigimera+Ltd.%3C%2Fa%3E+and+founded+the+software+incubator+project+%3Ca+href%3D%22http%3A%2F%2Fnetworld.to%22+target%3D%22_blank%22%3ENetworld%3C%2Fa%3E.%3Cbr%2F%3E%0A&amp;tags=day-in-my-life-as-entrepreneur%2Centrepreneur" type="text/html" />
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is the first post in the series
<a href="http://blog.alex-oberhauser.com/categories/day-in-my-life-as-entrepreneur/">A day in my life as an entrepreneur</a>.
In this series I will share my experience how it feels to be an entrepreneur and what challenges
we face in our day-to-day work. This is basically the story of my company
<a href="http://www.sigimera.com">Sigimera Ltd</a>. and how we survive outside the
big startup hubs. Although we profit from the current
startup hype around the world we are currently not directly part of it. But lets start from
the beginning a few years ago&hellip;</p>

<!--more -->


<p>All started 5 years ago during a dark and stormy winter night in an even darker cellar&hellip; No,
just kidding! The time span ago is approximately true, although it is always hard to say, because you don&rsquo;t
wake up and say: &ldquo;Today I start my new life as entrepreneur!&rdquo;. The rest is made up. Not all stereotypes are true.
Nevertheless&hellip; Around this time I have started my first smaller projects and a short time period after, it was
clear that I want to start my own company, in order to professionally support this projects. I should
mention that I have a background in business and studied at that time computer science at the University of Innsbruck.
This is a powerful combination that helps, but is not needed, so don&rsquo;t be afraid.
During this time I have exploited different technologies and switched pretty often between projects. The
time was not right for the one big project to rule them all.
This was the first phase were I have learned my craft and invested a lot of time to get the basic right and this
approach has never changed. Never stop learning!!!
Additional it was useful that I owned the domain <a href="http://networld.to">networld.to</a> and one server.
With this basic infrastructure I was able to setup a first working environment used for the software
development and get a feeling about workflows and what works and what doesn&rsquo;t for our team.</p>

<p>Now that I have bored you enough let me know in the comments what you expect from such a series of blog post.
Should I continue in chronologically order? Or should I move to the present and write from time to time
flashbacks? Do you want know something special? Every feedback is really appreciated.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[WTF!?! Do you need really another blog?]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.alex-oberhauser.com/2013/07/12/first-post/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-12T10:02:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.alex-oberhauser.com/2013/07/12/first-post</id>
    
      












      <link rel="payment" href="https://flattr.com/submit/auto?url=http%3A%2F%2Fblog.alex-oberhauser.com%2F2013%2F07%2F12%2Ffirst-post%2F&amp;user_id=obale&amp;title=WTF%21%3F%21+Do+you+need+really+another+blog%3F&amp;category=text&amp;description=Alex+Oberhauser+is+a+social+tech-entrepreneur+and+graduated+computer+scientist.+He+is+co-founder+and+CEO+of+%3Ca+href%3D%22http%3A%2F%2Fwww.sigimera.com%22+target%3D%22_blank%22%3ESigimera+Ltd.%3C%2Fa%3E+and+founded+the+software+incubator+project+%3Ca+href%3D%22http%3A%2F%2Fnetworld.to%22+target%3D%22_blank%22%3ENetworld%3C%2Fa%3E.%3Cbr%2F%3E%0A&amp;tags=first-post%2Cintroduction" type="text/html" />
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The short answer is <em>no</em>. The long answer is, it depends&hellip; For example if I
want to write some non-technical articles that are easier to read&hellip; or if I
want to share with you my experience as entrepreneur&hellip; And by the way since
when do I need a license for a blog!?</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The Networld blog (see <a href="http://blog.networld.to">http://blog.networld.to</a>) is only from time to time active.
Nevertheless I have decided to setup this blog in order to be more visible and
don&rsquo;t hide behind a meta-project. It gives me also the possibility to write
about stuff that is not directly related to Networld or one of the
sub-projects. But don&rsquo;t expect too much. I am not going to write about my private
life &ndash; who the hell cares anyway!?! Except of the three letter services of course.</p>

<p>On the other side I will give you information about the current efforts that
are related to my company Sigimera Ltd., but that don&rsquo;t fit into any other
channel. Other than that I have absolutely no clue what to write here. Maybe
I will tell you also about my motivation and how I overcome the
difficulties that are for free in a startup.</p>

<p>And at the end the full truth why this blog exists&hellip; Octopress running on
github.io is fun to use. Nothing more, nothing less.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
