<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: first-post | Blog of Alex Oberhauser]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.alex-oberhauser.com/categories/first-post/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.alex-oberhauser.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-09-22T11:57:31+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.alex-oberhauser.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Alex Oberhauser]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[alex.oberhauser@networld.to]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[WTF!?! Do you need really another blog?]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.alex-oberhauser.com/2013/07/12/first-post/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-12T10:02:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.alex-oberhauser.com/2013/07/12/first-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The short answer is <em>no</em>. The long answer is, it depends&hellip; For example if I
want to write some non-technical articles that are easier to read&hellip; or if I
want to share with you my experience as entrepreneur&hellip; And by the way since
when do I need a license for a blog!?</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The Networld blog (see <a href="http://blog.networld.to">http://blog.networld.to</a>) is only from time to time active.
Nevertheless I have decided to setup this blog in order to be more visible and
don&rsquo;t hide behind a meta-project. It gives me also the possibility to write
about stuff that is not directly related to Networld or one of the
sub-projects. But don&rsquo;t expect too much. I am not going to write about my private
life &ndash; who the hell cares anyway!?! Except of the three letter services of course.</p>

<p>On the other side I will give you information about the current efforts that
are related to my company Sigimera Ltd., but that don&rsquo;t fit into any other
channel. Other than that I have absolutely no clue what to write here. Maybe
I will tell you also about my motivation and how I overcome the
difficulties that are for free in a startup.</p>

<p>And at the end the full truth why this blog exists&hellip; Octopress running on
github.io is fun to use. Nothing more, nothing less.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
