<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: bitcoin | Blog of Alex Oberhauser]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.alex-oberhauser.com/categories/bitcoin/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.alex-oberhauser.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-06-29T19:56:45+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.alex-oberhauser.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Alex Oberhauser]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[alex.oberhauser@networld.to]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Crowd-Funding with Bitcoin (LinkedIn Post)]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.alex-oberhauser.com/2014/06/29/crowd-funding-with-bitcoin/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-29T19:38:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.alex-oberhauser.com/2014/06/29/crowd-funding-with-bitcoin</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>No crowd-funding effort is to small for Crowd-Funding with Bitcoin.
It does not matter if you collect funds for your next multi-billion business idea or the neighbourhood grill party.</p></blockquote>

<!-- more -->


<p>Currently crowd-funding gets a lot of traction and that not only in the
entrepreneurial space. No wonder, it allows to get money directly from
the community interested in the project or business idea that is
crowd-funded. Additional to the funds, the target market analysis is for
free and a community can develop around the project or company.</p>

<p>One of the downsides of current crowd-funding services are the high amount of
fees and that they are not tailored to smaller funding campaigns. Collecting
money from your fellow peers for the next grill party or for a birthday gift
is not really feasible, nor recommended with classical crowd-funding services.</p>

<p>Don&rsquo;t be sad, Crowd-Funding with Bitcoin can be exactly what you have looked
for. Bitcoin is a digital currency that has gained momentum in the last few
months. For all of you that have missed the Bitcoin hype, checkout the video
under bitcoin.org</p>

<p><strong>Why Crowd-Funding with Bitcoin is perfect for your next group activity?</strong></p>

<p>It is without doubt the easiest and fastest way to fund group activities like
trips or events where everybody finances a part.</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>It is not getting much easier.</strong> Paying is as easy as making a photo.</li>
<li><strong>Traceable without privacy concerns.</strong> Has everybody paid the promised
amount? Get notified or check if you have reached your goal. Not only for
the whole campaign, but on a personal level (only by the crowd-funding
campaign initiator).</li>
<li><strong>Cheaper as nearly all current solutions.</strong> Through the nature of
Bitcoin transactions are cheap and can be used for micro payments too.
No high and artificial service fees apply.</li>
<li><strong>Faster as nearly all current solutions.</strong> Somebody has forgotten to
pay a few minutes before the event starts? No problem. One transaction
takes only a few minutes.</li>
<li><strong>It is your money from the start.</strong> Cryptography makes it possible
that the received funds are only accessible by you. Not even the
crowd-funding service can access them.</li>
</ul>


<p>Bitcoin as new technology and financial means will bring crowd-funding to everybody and simplify the process.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
